acuonline.org 2011-06-01

# Associated Credit Union - Privacy

Associated Credit Union (ACU) is committed to protecting your privacy. This notice explains how we collect, use and safeguard your personal financial information. It describes ACU's privacy policy and practices which apply to the personal information we collect and disclose, including the parties who receive personal and sometimes nonpublic information from us, as we conduct the business of the credit union. This notice also contains an opportunity for you to instruct us not to release personal information to certain nonaffiliated third parties.

## Information We Collect

We collect non-public personal information about you from the following sources:

  * Information we receive from you on membership and loan applications and other forms;
  * Information about your transactions with us or others;
  * Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency; and
  * Information obtained when verifying the information you provide on an application or other forms, such as from your current or past employers or from other institutions where you conduct financial transactions; and
  * Information obtained at your request.

## Information We May Share

We are committed to providing you with competitive products and services to meet your financial needs, which may require that we share information about you with others to complete your transactions and provide you with a choice of products and services. In doing so, we may disclose all of the information we collect. Accordingly, we may disclose the following kinds of non-public personal information about you:

  * Information we receive from you on applications and other forms.
  * Information about your transactions with us or other companies that work closely with us to provide you with financial products and services.
  * Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency.

We may also disclose all the information we collect, as described above, to companies that perform marketing or other services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. To protect our members' privacy, we only work with companies that agree to maintain strong confidentiality protections and limit the use of information we provide.We do not allow these companies to sell the member information we provide to other third parties.

In order to conduct the business of the credit union, we may disclose non-public personal information about you as permitted or required by law. These disclosures typically include information to process transactions on your behalf, conduct the operations of ACU, follow your instructions as you authorize, or protect the security of our financial records.

## Certain Parties That Receive Information From Us  
Where You Can Request To Opt Out

We may disclose non-public personal information about you to the following types of third parties:

  * Financial service providers (such as those that provide mortgage, securities, credit card, and insurance services).
  * Non-financial companies (such as travel agencies, automobile dealers, retailers, direct marketers, Internet service providers, communications companies, manufacturers, service companies, cruise lines, car rental companies, hotels, airlines, publishers and organizations enclosing our products on services).
  * Other companies that provide consumer discount programs.

## Disclosure of Information About Former Members

If you terminate your membership with ACU, we will not share information we have collected about you, except as permitted or required by law.

## How We Protect Your Information

We restrict access to non-public personal information about you to those employees who have a specific business purpose in utilizing your data. Our employees are trained in the importance of maintaining confidentiality and member privacy. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations and leading industry practices to safeguard your non-public personal information.

## What You Can Do To Help Protect Your Privacy

ACU is committed to protecting the privacy of its members. Members can help by following these simple guidelines:

  * Protect your account numbers, card numbers, personal identification numbers (PINs) and passwords. Never keep your PIN with your debit or credit card which can provide free access to your accounts if your card is lost or stolen.
  * Use caution when disclosing your account numbers, social security numbers, and other personal information to other persons. If someone calls you, explains the call is on behalf of ACU and asks for your account number, you should be beware. Official credit union staff will have access to your information and will not need to ask for it.
  * Keep your information with us current. It is important that we have current information on how to reach you. If we detect potentially fraudulent or unauthorized activity or use of an account, we will attempt to contact you immediately. If your address or phone number at home or work changes, please let us know.

If you have questions concerning this notice, please do not hesitate to call us at (770) 448-8200. We are here to serve you.

## How To Opt Out

If you prefer that we do not disclose non-public personal information about you to such non-affiliated third parties, you may opt out of those disclosures. You may direct us not to make those disclosures (other than those permitted by law). If you wish to opt out of disclosures to non-affiliated third parties, you should do the following:

  * Complete the Opt Out Notice and mail it to us. 

You may opt out of these disclosures at any time. This option, by law, will not apply to disclosures that we make to companies that perform services on our behalf or to other financial institutions that have joint marketing agreements with us.

Once we receive your request not to make further disclosures, we will act as quickly as possible to stop disclosures. If you wish later to revoke your opt out election, you may do so by writing our Marketing Department at our main office.

Note to non-member joint account holders: Anyone of you may exercise the right to opt out, even if you are not actually a member of ACU. We will treat an opt out request from any one party to an account as if all of you direct us to not make disclosures to non-affiliated third parties to which the opt out right applies.

Unless we hear from you, we may share all the non-public personal information about you that we collect with businesses involved in insurance, financial services, travel, automobile sales, and others.

We believe that these types of products and services will be of value and interest to our membership. The specific companies that receive information from us are prohibited from using that information about you for any purpose other than what we agree by contract.
